In the last module, you learned how to use SQL in a nodejs application
and we did this at the example of a MySQL database which we want to use to store data.
Now we didn't complete the project with that SQL approach simply because in this module, we'll now implement
other features like for example working with the shopping cart with the help of sequelize.
This will still use a SQL database, still use the same
MySQL database actually behind the scenes or in the background as a database but the code we write
will be different.
Instead of SQL statements as we have them here and as we wrote them in the last module, we'll use
a third party package that allows us to work with javascript objects and convenient methods to create
new elements in the database, to edit them, to delete them or to find them and also to connect them
because you remember, a SQL database typically also works with relations
and we got lot of these in our current project.
So this is what we'll dive into in this module,
you'll learn what exactly sequelize,
this third party package is and how you can use it and we'll then implement our products and our cart
and so on in this module with sequelize.