Now let's work on the admin products page because there, I also want to display my products so that
we can interact with them.
So in admin.js
again,
get product still uses fetch all, now
it's of course a good practice for you to make this work with sequelize.
So definitely pause the video at this point and try to change this code here such that it does retrieve
the products and render them on the admin page.
Were you successful?
Well the code to you is of course the same code we used in the shop.js,
instead of fetch all, we'll use find all
and we don't use the callback function approach here because we're not using a callback function with
sequelize,
instead we have then and catch since we're using promises.
So let's console log our error in this case or pass our function we used as a callback before to then and
now here, we have our render function where we render the products. Therefore if I now reload this
admin page, I see my product here and I can now add it or delete it.
These however are two things that don't work, added doesn't work because I don't load the product
successfully and delete wouldn't work either.
So in the next lectures, we'll work on these two things.