Let's make edit work and for this, we first of all need to load the product that gets edited
so we're looking at the get edit product function in the admin.js controller.
We still want to retrieve that edit mode thing and the product ID as
we did it before. We can also still find a product by ID,
however as before, we'll not use a callback function here but our promise where we catch any errors we
might have
and then here we pass that function which gets the product to then. If we get no product, we redirect
which is fine and otherwise we'll render the view with our loaded product. With this tiny change already
if we save this and we reload the edit product page,
this is looking good,
the fields get populated with our values.
Now we just need to make sure that if we do change something and we save it, this does get saved to the
database correctly.
For that, we of course have to have a look at post edit product which gets called once we submit this
page. There, we retrieve all the data we need which is good but we won't save our product like this
instead here, we'll use the product model and first of all here, I want to find the element in the database
which we do want to change,
so I'll use find by ID here and I'll pass my prod ID to find it.
Then you know the game, we got then and catch,
so let's just handle any error by logging them for now and in then, let's work with the product
we retrieved, that product now needs to be updated.
So here we can simply do that by now saying product title equals updated title, so we can simply work with
all the attributes our product has per our model definition and change them,
please note this will not directly change the data in the database though, it will only do it locally in
our app, in our javascript app here for the moment.
So I can also change product title to updated price, to updated price, I can change the description to
updated desc and I can also change product image
url to updated image url. Now as I said this will not directly edit it in the database,
to do that we simply have to call product save.
This is another method provided by sequelize
and this now takes the product as we edit it and saves it back to the database.
If the product does not exist yet, it will create a new one
but if it does as this one, then it will overwrite or update the old one with our new values.
Now here we can again chain then and catch but to not start nesting our promises which would yield
the same ugly picture as nesting callbacks,
we can now return this here, so we return the promise which is returned by save and we can simply add
a then block here and this catch block, whoops, this catch block would catch errors both for this first promise
here
and for the second promise. This then block will now handle any success responses from this save promise
here,
so here we get back result and I will simply log updated product. Time to save that and to go back and
edit this by adding a couple of exclamation marks. Let's click update product now, we get redirected
to the products page,
here we don't see our change though but if we reload, we do
and in the database if we refreshed that here, we are of course also can see that change here.
Now do you know why we didn't immediately see that change on our admin products page though? Well the
reason is we redirect here
and as you learned, javascript and nodejs simply executes your code from top to bottom but async operations
like this simply get registered and started and then here for promises, we registered that this function
should be executed once the promise is resolved.
So it will not wait for this to finish but instead move onto the next line and the next line is this
one here,
so it will redirect before our promise is done.
So we should simply move redirect into the then block here. By the way this also means that for now if
we have an error, we never load a new page which is not the best user experience but we'll learn more
about error handling in a separate module of the course.
So for now, this is the setup I want to use
and with that if I now edit this and I remove the exclamation marks and I do let's say also change the
price here, if I now save that,
now we immediately see the new values because now we only redirect after the update was successful.