Updating was successful,
now let's also make sure we can delete products.
So in admin.js, I'm talking about the post delete product method here
now. We get the product ID which is good, now delete by ID does not exist in a sequelize
world, instead on the product we can call destroy and destroy allows us to destroy any product we find
through our options here
and these options allow us to for example add a where condition to narrow down which product to delete. We
can also use a different approach,
instead of calling destroy like this and adding a condition which product to find which is of course
fine,
we can also use find by ID again to find a product by that ID
and then again have our well known then and error, catch methods and in then, we know we got a product and
on that product,
we can now also call destroy
and now this will destroy the found product. We can return this because this will also yield a promise
and therefore add another then block which will execute once the destruction succeeded and there
we can if we want console log destroyed product and we can now also redirect thereafter.
We should redirect here to make sure we only redirect once the deletion succeeded. If we now go back
to our application and I add a new dummy product without any picture, just like this and we go to admin
products,
I got stuck on loading this automatically, I'll look into this a second
but if we go to admin products manually, we see it here if I click delete, this works.
Now one thing I noticed is that if I added a product here, we get stuck and we don't redirect,
so for adding a product host add product here, we don't do anything in then block, there we should of
course also redirect to /admin/product,
so basically to the same we redirect when deleting.
So now if we go back
and we add a new product again, this is working and now we can also delete the products here.
So this is now all working and now we can manage the products,
we can view them here,
now one thing we haven't touched at all are relations though because we don't just have products, we
all have a cart and eventually, we'll also have users.