What do I mean by association? You could also say relation. let's say in our project and that is basically
our project,
we have products, users, carts and at some point also orders.
Now if we want to connect all these things on and define how they work together, then a product would
probably belong to many carts because our users will have carts
therefore we have multiple users, multiple carts and therefore a product can belong to many carts because
of course different users can add the same product to their carts.
Each user only has one cart though,
so this is how we could relate that, a product
also can be part of multiple orders and a user can have multiple orders because you typically order more
than one thing. A user can also own multiple products
in a sense of this user created this product, so not own it in the sense of I bought it
but in the sense of hey I offer this product, I created it in the shop.
This is a rough outline of how we can communicate or relate different models
and this is what we can also reflect in sequelize. There I'll go to my app.js file here,
let's close the views,
I'll go to my app.js file and before I sync all my data to the database, I want to define my models.
So for this I will add more imports and I will import my product model by requiring this from the models
file and there the product file, add a models folder in the product file and I'll import my user model from
the user file in the models folder. With the two models imported, we can relate them and I will relate
them here in the same place where I sync
sequelize
but before I sync it. Here I can basically say that a product belongs to a user.
Now you can learn way more about these relations in the sequelize documentation.
There, there is a whole article about associations, which kind of associations exist and how you define them
in sequelize and which effect this has. I will show you some important implications in this model of course.
So back to our code, we are now setting up that for sequelize, a product belongs to a user and this
is now talking about a user created this product,
we're not talking about purchases at this point.
We can also configure this by passing a second argument which is optional, here
we can define how this relationship be managed and very important, we can define so-called constraints,
set them to true
and for example say that on delete,
so if a user is deleted, what should happen to any connected products? And here we can say cascade which
simply means well the deletion would then also be executed for the product,
so if we delete a user, any price related to the user would also be gone.
This is totally optional and you definitely need to learn a bit more about SQL to fully understand
your options here,
this is beyond the scope of this course but this can all be done with sequelize
and now we got this relation set up.
You can also define the inverse and say that one user has many products because one user can of course
add more than one product to the shop.
Now this is optional,
you don't need that,
you can basically replace belongs to with a has many call
but here I also like to define both directions to really make it clear how this relation works.
Now with this being set up, sequelize sync will not just create tables for our models but also define
the relations in our database as we define them here.
The one problem we have right now is that we already created the products table and therefore will
not override it with the new information and we can ensure that it will by setting force to true.
Of course a setting you wouldn't really use in production because you don't always want to overwrite
your tables all the time
but here during development, I want to reflect my new changes so I'll set this to true and therefore
after restarting, we indeed see a couple of statements were executed.
First of all it dropped any existing tables and then it created a new table, users with all the set up
and then it also creates a new products table and besides adding all the fields there,
it also defined that there is a new field, the user id field which is an integer and which is a foreign
key that references the ID field in the users table and that on delete, it should cascade
and on update cascade is the default.
So this is some meta setup in the database which sequelize now also added to connect our tables there
too.
And if we go to workbench and we right click on our database and set call refresh all, we see there
are two tables now
and indeed if we inspect products, we see that our product is gone because it recreated the table
but now besides created at and updated at that were added by sequelize,
there is a user ID field which was also added by sequelize and this will automatically be populated
by sequelize too
once we create products that are related to a user.
So let's make sure that we have a user because right now that table is empty and that we then can connect
users and products in our app.