To work with our new cart let's go to the controllers folder here and there to the shop.js file which
is where we have our cart related actions. Get products get product, get index, that is all working, get
cart however will not work.
In there, I want to use the cart associated with my existing user to get all the products in it and render
them to the screen.
For this, let's get rid of that code but I'll comment it out so that I easily can use my render function
again and
let's use request user, that's still the user stored in our request. By the way one important adjustment,
let's disable that force syncing again so that we don't always override any data we stored.
So let's go back to app.js, to shop.js excuse me and let's use the user we retrieve for every new
request and which we store in the request and there,
let's execute cart and let's look into this and see if this gives us anything meaningful.
If I now save this and I go to cart, it doesn't load the page
and if I go back we see undefined here,
so we can't access the cart like this.
But what we can do here is we can use our request user and get the cart which is associated to it. Let's
add then and catch,
here we'll get the cart and let's log the cart here.
If we save that and I reload this page, it still will not load
but now I get null here and not undefined.
Now the reason why we don't find anything here for either of the two approaches is that we got no carts
yet,
if we look into our database, carts is totally empty. Just as we create a user right at startup,
I'll create a cart for that user, so here I create a user.
Now in the next step where I get that user, I will also create a cart by adding user create cart, like this
and I don't need to pass any data in there because cart in the beginning will not hold any special
data, it just needs to be there.
I'll then return this and only listen in the next step
where I get my cart
so to say and with this now set up, you see an insert into carts call is done here. If we now have a look into
our carts,
we see now we get a cart associated to our user with the ID 1 and now if I try to reload that carts
page again, here we now get some output and this output is stemming from our get cart call here,
so from this console log where I do log that cart,
so now this is working. Now for completeness sake,
let's also console log request user cart
again, does this also work?
If I reload here, this still is the old log
but if I scroll above it, we still see undefined.
So this does not work, we can't access cart as a property here but we can call get cart to work with the
cart.
So now we've got the cart available, we loaded the cart from the database,
we know more about that cart here. With the cart available,
we can use it to fetch the products that are inside of it by returning carts get products.
Remember a cart is associated to products in our app.js file through belongs to many and sequelize
will do the magic of looking into cart item and so on,
so into this
in-between table. So we can get products, this was added by sequelize as a magic method
and therefore here in this then block, we'll have products available
and here I'll again just log any error I get.
But in the then block here, we should have the products that are in this cart and that of course means that
we can now render these products.
So here I will render
my products here,
store them in products and pass them to the view.
Now this will not work as expected though,
if I now reload this page, we see no products in cart.
Now we got no products in a cart but we'll see that later once we do have them, it'll also not work but
I'll come back to that,
for now let's just have a look at our query statement.
We can see that this is the statement executed by sequelize
and if you didn't see it before, here we can definitely see the advantage we have by using a package
like this.
We don't have to write that SQL statement on our own,
we use sequelize and let it do that behind the scenes.
So before I come back to what we will have to do regarding getting the cart products, let's make sure
we can add products to the cart.
So for now I'll get rid of all that logic here and I will focus on adding products to the cart in the
next step.