Now before we start using it, what is sequelize actually? Sequelize is a third party package, to be
precise
it's an object relational mapping library
and this is a pretty long name which simply means it does all the heavy lifting, all the SQL code
behind the scenes for us and maps it into javascript objects with convenience methods which we can call
to execute that behind the scenes SQL code so that we never have to write SQL code on our own.
It works like this,
we got our object let's say a user with a name, age, email and password but of course this can be anything,
could be a product, whatever you need and this is mapped to a database table by sequelize, so it automatically
creates that table for us even, it automatically sets up relations and tables even for us, it does all
that
and when we create a new user for example, we simply call a method on that user javascript object and
sequelize executes the SQL query or the SQL command that is required.
So instead of writing this on our own, we simply create a javascript object and work with that
and here would be one example using sequelize to create a new user which would behind the scenes execute the SQL
code we don't have to write. Sequelize
offers us the models to work with our database
as I showed you on the last slide and it allows us to define such models,
so basically define which data makes up a model and therefore which data will be saved in the database.
We can then instantiate these models, so these classes so to say, we can execute the constructor functions
or use utility methods to create let's say a new user object based on that model
so we have a connection here and we can then run queries on that.
That could be that we save a new user but it could also be that we find all users as an example
and here again, this always relates back to our model which we define with sequelize. And we can also
associate our models,
for example we could associate our user model to a product model.
So this is what sequelize does
but of course we dont just want to learn that in theory, we want to see that in practice.
So let's add sequelize to our project and let's slowly integrate it to manage our products in our cart and so
on through sequelize.