Our program is taking shape, we can't delete products from the cart yet though so we should definitely
also do that. To do that,
we still need the product ID
we want to delete
but now again, I will first of all get my cart for the user by accessing request user get cart and then
adding then and catch calls as we did it multiple times already
and in the then block here,
I know that I've got access to my cart and in that cart, I now want to find the products for this user
and to be precise, the products,
not all products but the product with that product ID.
So here I will return cart get products and then simply here where ID is equal to prod ID. In the next
then block we add, I therefore have my products and I have to extract that exact product I'm looking for as
the first element in the products array
and now I want to destroy that product but not in the products table of course but only in that in-between
cart item table that connects my cart with that product. To do that,
I can simply call product cart item using that magic field sequelize gives me to access the element in
the in-between table and then destroy
and that will remove it from that in-between table.
Now I will return this so that I can add another then block here with the result of this operation
if I would care
and then there I'll simply redirect back to the cart, where I should then not see that product anymore.
Let's give it a try.
If we reload the cart and I delete that one with quantity three, it's gone.
Got no errors here
and if we reload the cart items, we only have one element in there with quantity two and the other one
is gone indeed.
So this is how simple we can delete connected items in this in-between table.
Here are the example of the cart.