So our cart is looking pretty fine
and actually we have the old functionality again, now without storing anything in files but now working
with a database as we should.
Now one thing is missing and that are the orders. Now
I'll not add a real checkout flow here
but I want to have a checkout button in my cart which will basically for now immediately move all the
elements in this cart out of this cart,
so clear the cart and instead create a new order, an order that is related to a couple of products and
a user.
Now if you're feeling fancy, you can certainly try this on your own
otherwise we'll of course do it together here and we'll get there step by step
adding a simple checkout functionality.
Let's start with the model and for this, I'll create a new order.js file and copy my cart
item.js file,
move it in there,
import sequelize,
rename it here to order,
also here and now how should an order look like?
Well an order is in the end just an in-between table between a user to which the order belongs and then
multiple products that are part of the order and these products again do have a quantity attached to
them.
So just as we had cart items for the cart, I'll have order items for my order. So I can copy cart items
again, move that into order item and rename cart item here to order item, starting with a lowercase o
here in the string name definition and then it will have the same structure as an order, as in cart item
here in order item and the order itself will not have anything but the ID because the order essentially
is like the cart
here for me.
You could of course say an order has more information like an address and you could add this here,
you just have to make sure you add this for every order you create but that is essentially it.
Now regarding the relations, there is one important difference to the cart though.
If we go to the app.js file where we do set up all the relations, I'll import my order here from the order, whoops,
from the order file and I'll import my order item from the order item file
but now if we connect the models here at the bottom, we can say that an order belongs to a user and it doesn't
belong to many users because a single order is always belonging to one user who placed the order and the
user may of course have many orders, like this.
So this is not a many-to-many relationship,
it's a one to many relationship, one user can have many orders. Now an order however can belong to many
products and it does so with an in-between table which we specify with through which is our order item
table, like this and we can also define the inverse here if we want and that would be basically that a product
belongs to many orders but we can also leave it out here.
Now we get this set up.
now let me make sure we can sync again
so let's turn on forcing this.
If we now refresh our database, we should have new orders and order items, in orders
we see a connection to a user and in order items,
we see a connection to an order and to our product ID then. So this is now the set up we need to use
and I'll disable forcing this so that we don't overwrite tables all the time now.
So as a next step, let's make sure we have a checkout button and that this button does actually then
trigger something to create such a order.