Now that we can add orders,
one thing is missing and that is that we clear the cart,
I want to do this right after we edit the orders.
So down there I need to work with the cart and therefore first of all, I'll store it in a new variable, fetch
cart,
initially it's empty
and here once I got the cart, I'll store the cart in the fetch cart variable so that I can also use
it down there.
Now that cart should essentially drop all its cart items. Now I can use my fetch cart here to call
another method, set products for this cart and set the products to null.
Now let's return this and then add a new then block with the result of this operation where I simply
want to redirect.
Let's give it a try, let's save this and reload the cart page here, click order
now, we're on the orders page,
go back to the cart and we got no products in the cart because if we go into the workbench, we see that
the cart items indeed are empty because we dropped all the items in the cart by setting them to null,
this is how easy we can clean up the cart here.
So with that, we got all that logic done,
the last step I want to do here is that I actually show my orders and we can get rid of the checkout
page here for now because we have no such step at the moment.
So now let's make sure we also retrieve the orders correctly and can display them on our orders page. For
this here,
I'll first of all get my user
and now I'm interested in the orders of this user which I can get with get orders,
a magic method added by sequelize,
thanks to our associations. Here we again get a promise, let's log any potential errors we get
and in the then block, I know that I have my orders.
This is where I want to render my orders page therefore and I will pass a new variable into that
page,
the orders variable which simply stores all the retrieved orders. So with that I got my orders for this
user,
now let's go to the respective view in the views folder,
here's the orders.ejs file which always shows nothing there.
Now obviously that's not what I always want to show, instead I only want to show nothing there or no
orders placed yet,
whatever you like
if we got no orders,
so I'll first of all add a normal ejs statement where I check if orders length is smaller or equal than zero,
then we probably have no orders,
so in this case I want to display nothing there.
Now else and that is of course an important part,
let's also close that statement of course with the closing curly brace,
else I want to output my orders and for now I'll do this in a very ugly way with an unordered list of list
items which I repeat for every order,
so again ejs time to loop through all orders with forEach for example. Now forEach
as you know takes an anonymous function which gives us access to every order
then we repeat this code here for every order and then here, we close the curly brace and the bracket
of our forEach method, we can add a semi-colon if you want
and now this is executed for every order we got.
Now every order we got has a couple of products that belong to the order,
so for every order I have here, I will output a h1 tag with the ID, order.Id, output like this and
below that another nested unordered list with more list items where I loop through the products belonging
to the order,
so here I'll have order and then it's order item,
that is our connected model so to say, forEach because that will be a list of all the related items
and here I get my item.
Let's close this here and let's also close the forEach syntax then down there
and now this list item is repeated for every item in this order and there I simply want to output
the title, so output item title.
Keep in mind this is a product so it will have a title and then maybe in normal parentheses, I'll output
item quantity and this will not work,
I can already tell you that. If I save that, I get another error actually
and that is simply coming from the fact that I deleted one route, the checkout route,
we need to delete it here too
so I deleted the action, we need to delete the route too
but still if I reload the orders page now, this will just crash here because I have an ejs syntax
error though,
let's quickly fix that.
Ok here for item quantity, you need to close that
but even after this change, this will not work now because order is not defined because that should be
orders forEach but now because we can't loop through order item here, this does not work.
And to understand this, let's have a look at our shop.js controller file and let's output orders here
and let's see what exactly we get. For this let's now reload the page,
it will still break of course but now we can have a look at the output there,
we want to scroll up. There is what we log with this line, console log orders and there we can see that
we do have an array of orders but an order does not have an order item key,
this is not provided by sequelize.
If we also want to fetch the related products to an order, we have to pass an object here where we set
include to an array with the field products or the element products as a string.
Now why products? Because in app.js, we associate an order to many product, products of course
and if we have a look at our model, the product model has the name product. Sequelize pluralizes this and
then we can use a concept called eager loading where we basically instruct sequelize
hey if you are fetching all the orders, please also fetch all related products already and give me back
one array of orders
that also includes the products per order.
Now this only works of course because we do have a relation between orders and products as set up in
app.js here and now we can load both together.
This will still not make our template work immediately
but now we got orders with more data in them.
Each order will now have a products array and with that in mind, we can go back to our view here, to the
orders view and tweak that. We can loop through the orders and every order will have an ID, that's fine.
Now our order will still not have a order item but it will have a products list and now we can loop
through all the products and each item which is now simply a product and therefore we can name it as such
to make this clear, each product of course has a title which we can output and it does not have a quantity
but the product will now have an order item key which then stores the quantity for that product
in that order. And now if we reload this page, we do see our orders with the nested products in there,
not the most beautiful presentation you have for sure but this is how it actually works.
We also see there is one dummy order that was created accidentally in between with no products and we
can always verify this by looking into the database, we get four order items related to orders with
the ID 9 and 11 in the orders, we got 9, 10 and 11 so indeed there is the order with the ID 10 which has
no items.
We can simply clear it by
right clicking on it here,
delete row,
apply apply and close and now if we reload the orders page, it's gone and we only see these two orders.
So this is now working and now we get the full flow,
we got a user who is related to created products, we can edit the products, we can delete the products,
we can add products to the cart.
We can then also create an order based on the data in our cart,
we can view product details and so on.
So this is all working fine as it should
and with that, we get the set up we need for now.
This gave you an introduction to sequelize and definitely dive into the official docs to play around
with that and learn more about it and how it works.