That's it for the SQL part of this course. You learned about SQL, that it's a database philosophy or
schema engine type that uses strict data schemas and relations in the databases that use SQL and
that you can easily connect to such databases with nodejs, with packages like MySQL too. There we
had to write all the SQL queries manually though
and you also have to configure the database manually, add tables manually, set up relations and that is
a lot of work and definitely something you need to learn
in addition to nodejs, it's its own language essentially
or you use packages like sequelize. Sequelize allows you to not write SQL queries but instead interact
with your database through models you define and not just models but also relations, so-called associations
in the sequelize world.
That gives you a lot of magic methods that allow you to easily connect data, add data, delete data,
basically what you saw in this module.
Now you could easily create an entire course just about SQL and sequelize
and that is not what this course is, it's the complete node course, not the complete sequelize
course. I strongly encourage you to dive into the sequelize docs if you plan on continuing with that to
learn all the ins and outs of this package and simply play around with it, build your own demo applications
and try out the different features, different types of relations and so on.
We'll move on here and we'll learn about a different way of storing data with a NoSQL approach in mongodb.
This is what we'll dive into in the next modules.