With the connection set up, let's go into our models folder and there to the product.js file
and there we can actually delete everything.
We don't need all of that right now, we'll write it from scratch. Here I
first of all need to import two things.
The first thing is sequelize itself,
so again I will require, whoops, require sequelize here and that will give me back a class or constructor
function
hence I name this here with a capital S.
The next thing I'll import is my database connection pool managed by sequelize,
I'll also name this sequelize but with lowercase s,
so I'll basically import what I export in my database.js file. Here
I will import this by requiring and then go up one level into util and then there to the database.js
file.
Now with these two things imported,
we can now define a model that will be managed by sequelize.
So here in this file below my imports, I'll create a new constant and I'll name it product because in the product.js
file
I want to define my product model.
Now this model is not defined as a class as we did it before
but instead I use sequelize with the lowercase s,
so my database connection pool which is more than a connection pool, it's actually a fully configured
sequelize environment which does also have the connection pool but also all the features of the sequelize
package
and there we can define a new model by calling define. The first name that is the model name and by the
way, here in the suggestion you also see an example and so on
as you do in the official docs of course.
Now the model name typically is a lowercase name and I'll name it product like this,
you are free to name this however you want but to follow along smoothly,
I recommend taking this name. The second argument defines the structure of our model and therefore also of
the automatically created database table.
This will be a javascript object and in there, we simply define the attributes or fields
our product should have, for example I want to have an ID.
Now an ID is then in turn defined with an object where I configured this attribute,
there for example we set the type and the type is now one of the types defined by the sequelize package.
So now I use sequelize with a capital S,
so from this import here and there you find a bunch of types like number or string,
so not var, char and so on but here you have the more javascript-ish names I could, would say and I want to
use an integer here because my ID will be a number starting at 1 and then incrementing. To make it increment,
I also configured this attribute to be auto-incrementing by setting auto-increment to true
and in case you're wondering how I do know all of that,
well again you find that in the official docs. On docs.sequelizejs.com,
you can dive into sequelize, learn more about how it works and how you can configure it and under model
definition,
you learn all about how to define a model, how you can define your different tags for the model and you
also see a list of all the supported data types, like the integer we just used.
So this is where you can learn more about this and I can tell you that I want this to be auto-incrementing
so I will set auto-increment to null, to true.
I also don't want to allow this value to be empty, so I will allow null to false because I don't want
to allow null values in there.
Last but not least,
I'll set primary key to true to basically define this as the primary key of the table which is an important
concept in SQL databases for retrieving the data and then also for later defining relations. With
that defined, a product of course also has other fields, for example a title.
Now we can again define a javascript object to configure it in detail or if you just want to set the type,
you can also use sequelize and then the type,
so this is a shortcut in case you only want to set the type, though you could argue that we also at least
want to set that this should never be null
but here as a demo, I will just assign the type. For the price I'll go back to the javascript object and
set the type to sequelize and then double and I will again set allow null to false to not allow null
values here. Then I will set my image
url here again to a javascript object where I set the type to sequelize string and I will set
allow null to false to not allow null values here. And last but not least, I also want to have a description
which also will have a type that is of type sequelize string and I will set allow null to false.
Now this is my product model,
last but not least we need to export it.
So below my model definition here,I'll simply use module exports and export my product here,
so this constant in which I define, store the defined model,
this gets exported here.
And with that, we made a huge step forward
and we can now start using this product.
Now let's see how we use it over the next lectures.