We define the product model
and I mentioned that we can now work with this model to create new products and so on
but for this, we of course also need a product table in our database and there right now we got no tables
because I deleted the products table earlier in this module.
I also mentioned that sequelize can create these tables for you and it indeed can. Now to create tables
for you,
you just have to tell sequelize to do that
and I'll do that in the app.js file. In there
I want to ensure that all my models are basically transferred into tables or get a table that belongs
to them whenever we start our application
and if the table already exists, it will of course not override it by default though we can tell
it to do so.
Now in my app.js file which is the file execute when I do start my program,
I want to import from the database file as I did it before, I'll just rename it to sequelize because
I do import my sequelize object with a lower case s because I'm importing from my own utility database
set up file and then towards the end of this file,
let's say here, I want to call sequelize
and then there's a special method, the sync method. The sync method has a look at all the models you defined
and keep in mind you defined your models in your model files by calling sequelize defined on that same
sequelize object,
so it is aware of all your models and it then basically creates tables for them.
That is what sync does,
it syncs your models to the database by creating the appropriate tables
and if you have them, relations. So here I will call sync and then I can listen to the result of this,
let's see what we get back as a response here or what we get back as a value here and we can also of
course catch potential errors that occurred
and if an error occurred here, well then we can essentially also log that and I only want to let's say
start my server if we somehow made it into then, let's see what this gives us.
If I now run npm start here, it starts up and we see there is some log output.
If you scroll up quite a bit because we got back a complex object, you see that this is a default log
thrown by sequelize, it executed this SQL query for us without us writing this query.
It created a table
if it did not exist yet which it named product, products and that is that automatically inferred name
because we named our model product, it automatically pluralizes that and then it assigned a couple of
fields there which it configured according to our model definition.
And then this is the return value we get back,
basically our sequelize object you can tell
and if I now quit this server with control c, clear the console and rerun npm start, you'll see it runs
this again
but it does not overwrite the existing table because we have that if not exists check in there automatically.
So we can run this again without issues
and our server starts up even if this table already exists,
we still make it into then.
Now I will comment out that result log because I don't want to have this long object every time, in the
console every time we start this.
So now I just get MySQL query here and if we now have a look at the workbench and we right click
on our database and click on refresh all, we see that under tables, we get a products table and if we inspect
that with this icon, we see all the fields we defined and that is added by sequelize to new fields, created
at and updated at.
So it automatically manages some timestamps for us,
we could
disable this
but I actually like this feature,
so we get these automatically managed fields too.
This is how we sync our tables to the database and what sequelize does for us,
and with that, we're now ready to use that.